# Wanjala Simiyu

120-30200, Kitale, TransNzoia•+254759533824•wannjalas@gmail.com• linkedin.com/in/wanjalasimiyu•https://twitter.com/wannjala• https://wannjala.github.io/portfolio\_website/

## **Content Marketer**

I'm an experienced Content Writer and Marketer, having been involved in various engagements as a ghostwriter since 2018. The past 18 months were particularly special because I had the opportunity to create almost 100 blog posts for a PIM vendor. This experience was enriching because it allowed me to learn as much as possible about PIM and DAM solutions for B2B businesses. I'm also actively building Data Engineering and Data Science skills.

#### 

- Tailored Content: I specialize in creating content that connects with specific audiences.
- Results-Driven: My work contributes to increased visibility and engagement.
- Diverse Portfolio: I've covered a wide range of subjects, enhancing my adaptability and research skills.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Catsy.com • Remote 04/2023 - 09/2024

Catsy is a PIM and DAM vendor headquartered in Chicago, USA. Its PIM and DAM are bundled into a single SaaS product designed for brands, retailers, and distributors to manage and synchronize product attributes and digital assets from a single source of truth. I took charge of the company's blog section in April 2023 until the contract lapsed in September 2024.

Freelancing • Remote. 07/2018 - 09/2023

I have been involved in various projects since I began my writing career in 2018. Mostly I did news reports for cryptocurrency sites. I later transitioned to the Finance and Statistics disciplines, where I ghostwrote for sites like Finmasters.com, GuruFocus.com, and InsiderMonkey.com.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor Of Economics And Statistics in Economics**

The University Of Nairobi • Second Class Upper 09/2012 - 12/2016

## **Kenya Certificate Of Secondary Education**

Mang'u High School ● Grade: A- 01/2007 - 12/2010

## **Kenya Certificate Of Primary Education**

Dekko Academy • 413/500 Marks. 01/1998 - 12/2006

#### **PROJECTS**

## Fortune Global 500 Web Scraper

10/2024 - 10/2024

Even as I polish my writing skills, I'm also working hard to stay sharp with regard to Python programming. To that end, I initiated a web scraping project, where I created a Python script that crawls Fortune.com and yields the list of the 500 largest companies in the world every year since 1995. Like the previous projects, this one taught me how to create solutions and think critically. I believe the knowledge from this project helps to sharpen my research skills, which may come in handy for content writing jobs.

Here is the link to the project's GitHub repository: https://github.com/wannjala/fortune500-scraper

Sales Data Analysis 01/2023 - 01/2023

I wrote a tutorial on how to analyze data using Python. I used a Sales dataset from Kaggle.com and prepared an article, which I posted on Dev.com. This project helped me to soak in complex Python programming concepts and understand how to apply programming skills. Additionally, I learned how to decompose complex information into content that anyone can read and understand.

Here is the link to the project: https://dev.to/wannjala/data-analysis-with-python-9h5

#### **Portfolio Website**

I needed to prove to myself that the HTML, CSS, and JavaScript lessons I had taken were not in vain, so I created my portfolio website. This project was easy to accomplish, but the satisfaction I got from seeing the site live was something else. I learned how to solve problems and work around obstacles to deliver a project even though no one had asked me to.

Here is the link: https://wannjala.github.io/portfolio website/

## **SKILLS**

Excellent English writing and speaking skills., Great interpersonal Skills, Python programming, Teamwork, A keen eye for detail, Great researcher.